<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../xslt/tml1.xslt"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="../css/tml.css"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="../css/all.css"?>
<thakbong xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
    <project id="thakbong">
        <description>
        <name language="English" script="Latin" ucd="LATIN">Thakbong 讀墓, A Research and Documentation Project at APLAC, the Research
        Center for Asia Pacific Languages and Cultures</name>
            <creator>Oliver Streiter</creator>
            <initiator>Oliver Streiter, Yoann Goudin</initiator>
            <responsible>Oliver Streiter, Yoann Goudin, James X. Morris, Zhan
            Ya-Qing</responsible>

            <include href="tmlCollaborator.xml" parse="xml" />
            <include href="tmlContributor.xml" parse="xml" />

            <div ucd="LATIN" author="Oliver">The Thakbong project is an open-ended project, which in
            its current stage can best be described as a digital endeavor to document,
            archive and research epigraphy in the Taiwan Strait and beyond. The
            documentation consist of primary data, mostly photos, and secondary data,
            which are derived through the annotation of the photos. This data set
            contains the secondary data. The primary data, the photos, are linked from
            this file to their current repository in the cloud.</div>
            <div ucd="LATIN" author="Oliver">The process of creating secondary data from the photos
            involves the transcription and translation of inscriptions, as well as the
            classification and description of entities. These entities can be sites,
            objects, physical or semiotic in nature, and events.</div>

            <div ucd="LATIN" author="Oliver">The classification process relates the entities that we document, a house, an altar, a tombstone, a phrase, to one or more labels of a closed set of labels. These labels can be useful for analysis techniques as used in the Digital Humanities, such as the drawing of time-lines or the drawing of maps. Yet, these labels, one has to remember are human-made. They are valid within one culture, within one time, within one language. We don't try to give universal definitions of entities and their types and properties beyond specific languages and cultures. Doing so would a) not be possible, and b) not always be meaningful, as the meaning resides in the specific language and culture. Instead, we try to keep track of the names and properties of the entities that communities and cultures assign to them. We also try to keep track of the labels that have been assigned to these entities in the past in the academic publications within a certain, time, language and culture. Different labels assigned to the same entity can reveal different aspects of the entity. Different lables even can be seemingly contradictory. This is not a problem, as research in the humanities is not only research on entities created by humans, but also on the humans who classify and try to understand them. It is natural that the same entity can be classified and named differently in different times, languages and cultures.</div>
            <div ucd="LATIN" author="Oliver">The classification process relates the entities that we document, a house, an altar, a tombstone, a phrase, to one or more labels of a closed set of labels. These labels can be useful for analysis techniques as used in the Digital Humanities, such as the drawing of time-lines or the drawing of maps. Yet, these labels, one has to remember are human-made. They are valid within one culture, within one time, within one language. We don't try to give universal definitions of entities and their types and properties beyond specific languages and cultures. Doing so would a) not be possible, and b) not always be meaningful, as the meaning resides in the specific language and culture. Instead, we try to keep track of the names and properties of the entities that communities and cultures assign to them. We also try to keep track of the labels that have been assigned to these entities in the past in the academic publications within a certain, time, language and culture. Different labels assigned to the same entity can reveal different aspects of the entity. Different lables even can be seemingly contradictory. This is not a problem, as research in the humanities is not only research on entities created by humans, but also on the humans who classify and try to understand them. It is natural that the same entity can be classified and named differently in different times, languages and cultures.</div>

            <div ucd="LATIN" author="Oliver">Multiple and eventually contradicting classifications, more than an obstacle to an analysis, may form e key to the understanding of the social reality of the entity. If some people discribe the Hagia Sophia as church, others as mosque, still others as historical monument, this points to transformations, social and religious conflicts, eventually to harmonious and tollerant coexistence of cultures of religions. Multiple and contradictory classifications of entities are a constitutional component of entities that point to why and eventually how they have to be documented. </div>

<div ucd="LATIN" language="English" author="Oliver">A description is different from a classification. A description tries mainly to convey information to people living in other times or other regions. It addresses people who cannot or can no longer visit the documented sites. A description thus tries to give them the best possible impression of sites and objects, which in a rapidly changing world are mostly bound to disappear. A description is written without a rigid classification scheme in mind. Descriptions tell thus as much about the described entity, as about the author of the description. A description thus reveals the concern and bias of the researcher and by means of this allows to gauge the interest and the quality of the data.</div>

            <div ucd="LATIN">Attempts to clarify what you find in the dataset.</div>
            <include href="tmlDefinitions.xml" parse="xml" />

            <include href="tmlSubProjects.xml" parse="xml" />

            <div ucd="LATIN">Access all XML-files of the Thakbong project.</div>
            <include href="tmlSiteMap.xml" parse="xml" />

        </description>

        <copyright index='CC BY-NC 4.0 Deed'>
            <name language="English" script="Latin" ucd="LATIN">Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International</name>
            <url>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</url>
        </copyright>

    </project>
</thakbong>
