<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../xslt/tml1.xslt"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="../css/tml.css"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="../css/all.css"?><thakbong xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"><project id="thakbong"><name>Thakbong 讀墓, A Research and Documentation Project at APLAC, the ResearchCenter for Asia Pacific Languages and Cultures</name><description><creator>Oliver Streiter</creator><initiator>Oliver Streiter, Yoann Goudin</initiator><responsible>Oliver Streiter, Yoann Goudin, James X. Morris, ZhanYa-Qing</responsible><collaborator><description><div>People who joined our field work activities and collectedphotos.</div></description><xi:include href="tmlCollaborator.xml" parse="xml"/></collaborator><contributor><description><div>People who contributed with their photos to the development ofthe data base.</div></description><xi:include href="tmlContributor.xml" parse="xml"/></contributor></description><description><h2>Thakbong, Defining the Undefinable</h2><div author="Oliver">The Thakbong project is an open-ended project, which inits current stage can best be described as a digital endeavor to document,archive and research epigraphy in the Taiwan Strait and beyond. Thedocumentation consist of primary data, mostly photos, and secondary data,which are derived through the annotation of the photos. This data setcontains the secondary data. The primary data, the photos, are linked fromthis file to their current repository in the cloud.</div><div author="Oliver">The process of creating secondary data from the photosinvolves the transcription and translation of inscriptions, as well as theclassification and description of entities. These entities can be sites,objects, physical or semiotic in nature, and events.</div><div author="Oliver">Classification relates the entities that we document, ahouse, an altar, a tombstone, a phrase, to one or more labels of a closed setof labels. These labels can be useful for analysis techniques as used in theDigital Humanities, such as the drawing of time-lines or the drawing of maps.Yet, these labels, one has to remember are human-made. They are valid withinone culture, within one time, within one language. We don't try to giveuniversal definitions of entities and their types and properties. Doing sowould a) not be possible, b) not always meaningful, as the meaning resides inthe specific language and culture. Instead, we try to keep track of the namesand properties of the entities that communities and cultures assign to them.We also try to keep track of the labels that have been assigned to theseentities in the past in the academic publications within a certain, time,language and culture. Different labels assigned to the same entity can focuson different aspects of the entity. They even can be contradictory. This isnot a problem, as research in the humanities is not only research on entitiescreated by humans, but also on the humans who classify and try to understandthem. It is natural that the same entity can be classified and nameddifferently in different times, languages and cultures.</div><div author="Oliver">Descriptions are different from classifications.Descriptions try to convey information mainly to people living in other timesor other regions, to people who cannot or can no longer visit the documentedsites as the sites no longer exist. The descriptions thus try to give themthe best possible impression of sites and objects, which in a rapidlychanging world are mostly bound to disappear. The transcriptions are writtenwithout a rigid scheme or a research question, or a classification scheme inmind and tell as much about the author of the description as about the site.The descriptions reveal the concern and bias of the researcher and thus allowto gauge the interest and the quality of the data.</div><div author="Oliver">The secondary data are available under the licensespecified below. The primary data, images and videos, are less freelyavailable. Basically, there is a different license for each media file,depending on who took the photo or video when, where and of what. Most photosand videos have been taken in the last 20 years and thus show the livingenvironment of contemporaneous people, their habits, their houses, theirtombs, their practices. We are preparing these data to become freelyavailable in the future, trying to preserve the privacy of the people andcommunities we documented to some degree. If you want to use photos of videosyou find linked from this archive, please contact the people signingresponsible for this project. In most cases they will grant you the right touse media files for academic and non-commercial purposes if you refer to thisarchive, its location and, if known, the reserachers who took the photo.Below the name and URL for the license of the secondary data.</div></description><description><div><xi:include href="tmlDefinitions.xml" parse="xml"/>Attempts to clarify whatyou find in the dataset.</div></description><description><div><xi:include href="tmlSubProjects.xml" parse="xml"/>Virtual sub-divisions ofthe Thakbong data set for research and rapid overviews.</div></description><description><div><xi:include href="tmlSiteMap.xml" parse="xml"/>Access all XML-files of theThakbong project.</div></description><copyright index='CC BY-NC 4.0 Deed'><name language="LGENG">Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International</name><url>https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/</url></copyright></project></thakbong>