<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../xslt/tml1.xslt"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="../css/tml.css"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="../css/all.css"?><project id="subprojects" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">	<h2>Thakbong Projects and Sub-Projects -- Virtual Subsets for Research and Data Exploration</h2>	   <description>		   <div>The Thakbong project is divided into various, potentially overlapping sub-projects. A sub-project can be wide and reflect a domain of interest of some researchers at a given time. Other sub-project may be more specific, trying to answer just one research question. Dividing the overall Thakbong project into sub-projects is a methodological decision, which allows to focus on some specific aspects of fieldwork, data types or data structures and then eventually transfer these aspects, annotation schemes or insights to other parts of the data-set.		   </div>		   <div>The different sub-projects thus push and pull the Thakbong archive into different dimensions. However, as all sub-project follow the same data format and annotation scheme, data of all sub-projects can be freely combined to conduct more advanced and interesting research. To achieve this, we try to annotate data categories that have been created for one research question, e.g. for a specific region, also for data collected in other regions. We thus hope to create a data repository that goes beyond providing approaches to specific research questions and stimulates the formulation of a multitude of research questions.		   </div>		   <div>In the context of browsing and exploring the data of the database online, the sub-projects can also been understood as a way to search sites, objects and inscriptions. As the entire data set is very large and difficult to search through, any subdivision might help to find if you know what you are looking for. 		   </div>		   <div>Sub-projects, however, are only virtual divisions of the total Thakbong data-set. Similar to so-called views in relational data bases, they are sets of data that are created on-the-fly from a larger set of data. The overall data, annotated and stored in XML, consists conceptually of one large file, connected through xml-include commands. For practical reasons, however, the total set of data is subdivided, mainly according to principles of geographic inclusion. Thus for geographic subdivisions, it is best to search the data along file names. However, if the interest is thematic, crossing different geographies, sub-projects come into play. They are defined by queries of the data, i.e. quasi-logical expression that select a sub-set of the annotated items. On this server, the sub-projects are queried through the XML-specific programming language XSLT, which through the document() function can access different geographic data-files and return thematically related XML-entities that match the X-Path expression. When downloading the entire data set, such thematically oriented questions can be re-stated or re-formulated flexibly in other programming languages, e.g. in R or Python. 		   </div>		   <div>   Currently the following projects are distinguished:		   </div>	   </description>	   <project id="landforms">		   <name short="Landform" language="LGENG">Geologies, Geographies and Cultures in Southeast Asia</name>		   <responsible>Oliver Streiter and Ya-Qing Zhan</responsible>		   <description>			   <div author="Oliver">This project aims at the documentation of land forms, and their relation to human cultures. Land forms, like "mountain' or "lake" are socio-cultural descriptions of landscapes or parts of those landscapes. These land forms are either the direct or indirect result of human intervention, we speak of cultural landscapes. Alternatively, humans are interacting with the land forms they cannot change in order to increase their chances of survival. These interactions can be spiritual, social, religious, conceptual or of any other nature. The conceptualization of these land forms in terms and concepts of a language are the first step necessary for a culture or a community to interact with these natural environment.</div>		   <img alt="This image show a spiritual sites at the border of a village of Penghu." url="/2020/10/02/DATE20201002TIME102657GEOBOOLyesLONGE119517915LATN23628883DIR301ALT0SIZE11472THUMB4642ORIGHannaDSCN0164.jpg"/>		   </description>		   <url>/tml/menuLandform.html</url>	           <project id="archipelagoes">		       <name short="Archipelagoes" language="LGENG">Archipelagoes in Southeast Asia</name>	               <project id="Penghu">		            <name short="Archipelagoes" language="LGENG">Penghu</name>	                    <project id="generals">	   <name short="generals" language="LGENG">Penghu Five Generals -- 澎湖營頭</name>	   <responsible>Oliver Streiter, Ya-Qing Zhan and Yoann Goudin</responsible>	   <description>		                    <div author="Oliver">This project inherits its focus a) from the very large "Penghu" project and b) the "Geologies, Geographies and Cultures in Southeast Asia" project as the "five generals" arranged around the villages of Penghu define a interface between the cultural, spiritual and natural environment of their villages. These generals, known as "five generals" can be found as well in other regions. Yet, the number of generals, not five, their names and their forms defy most descriptions of the five generals that assume a cultural uniformity of this phenomenon. More particularly, we find villages on Penghu with more that five "five generals". We also find villages, where generals are blended with Earth Gods, Shigandang or other spiritual practices that are supposed to protect a village. At the same time, the influence of the natural environment on the positioning and orientation of the generals cannot be ignored. In many cases generals oppose the fierce winter monsoon wind from NNE. In other cases, the generals enhance the coast-line. Finally, even the cardinal directions are challenged or redefined in villages, where the system of generals is turned either by 90 or 180 degrees with respect to the geographic standard directions. In addition, given the great variety of realizations of the five generals, a detailed documentation of the five generals allows to draw 'dialect maps' of cultural practices, showing, surprising or not, that the greatest cultural influence on the cultural practice of a village are the cultural practices of a neighboring village.</div>	   </description>	   <xi:include href="tmlProjectGeneral.xml" parse="xml"/>	   Related:	   <xi:include href="tmlProjectShigong.xml" parse="xml"/>	   <xi:include href="tmlExampleShigandang.xml" parse="xml"/>	   </project><project id="gardens">	   <name short="Gardens" language="LGENG">The Orientation of Gardens</name>	   <responsible>Oliver Streiter</responsible>	   <collaborator>		   <collab><latin>Ya-Qing Zhan</latin></collab>	   </collaborator>	   <description>		   <div>This project can be understood as a sub-project of either the the Thakbong sub-project "Geologies, Geographies and Cultures in Southeast Asia" or the Thakbong sub-project "Documenting Culture and Resilience in Southeast Asia".</div>		   <div>This project simply tries to capture the orientation of gardens in relation to their geo-references, so that this orientation can be related to environmental conditions, such as the slope and its direction, the location of the sea or the main wind direction.</div>		   <div>Most data in this project have been collected in Summer 2021 when Oliver Streiter spent several months in Penghu.</div>	   </description>	   <archives>	       <archive>	           <name>Depositar</name>	           <url>https://data.depositar.io</url>		   <repository>	               <name language="LGENG">Penghu Gardens</name>	               <name script="LGTRAD">澎湖菜宅 </name>	               <url>https://data.depositar.io/en/organization/thakbong</url>	               <format>CSV</format>	               <format>KMZ</format>	               <update>2022-01-01</update>	               <entities>204</entities>	           </repository>	       </archive></archives>	   <url>/tml/menuGarden.html</url></project><project id="houses">	   <name short="Houses" language="LGENG">The Orientation of Houses</name>	   <responsible>Oliver STREITER and Ya-Qing ZHAN</responsible>	   <description>		   <div> This project can be understood as a sub-sub-project of either the the Thakbong sub-project "Geologies, Geographies and Cultures in Southeast Asia", or the Thakbong sub-project "Documenting Culture and Resilience in Southeast Asia".</div>		   <div>This project simply tries to capture the geo-references and the orientation of houses. It is the purpose to relate this orientation of houses to environmental conditions, such as slope and its direction, the location of the sea or the main wind direction.</div>		   <div>Most data in this project have been collected in Summer 2021 by Oliver STREITER on Penghu.</div>		   <img alt="This image shows a house in Penghu" style='width:75%' url="/2021/09/30/DATE20210930TIME114407GEOBOOLyesLONGE119568715LATN23618297DIR37ALT0SIZE11472THUMB4765ORIGOliverDSCN0385.jpg"/>		   <img alt="This image shows a hand holding a compass, measuring the direction of a house in Penghu." style='width:75%' url="/2021/09/30/DATE20210930TIME114347GEOBOOLyesLONGE119568672LATN23618220DIR114ALT0SIZE11472THUMB4223ORIGOliverDSCN0382.jpg"/>	   </description>	   <archives>	       <archive>	           <name>Depositar</name>	           <url>https://data.depositar.io</url>		   <repository>	               <name language="LGENG">Penghu House Geo-references</name>	               <name script="LGTRAD">澎湖房子的基本空間資訊</name>	               <url>https://data.depositar.io/en/organization/thakbong</url>	               <format>CSV</format>	               <format>KMZ</format>	               <update>2022-06-11</update>	               <entities>1100</entities>	           </repository>	       </archive></archives>	   <url>/tml/menuHouse.html</url></project>	               </project>	               <project id="Okinawa">		            <name short="Okinawa" language="LGENG">Okinawa</name>	               </project>	               <project id="Islands">		            <name short="Islands" language="LGENG">Islands</name>	               </project>	           </project>	   </project><project id="settlements">	   <name short="Settlement" language="LGENG">Documenting Culture and Resilience in Southeast Asia</name>	   <responsible>Ya-Qing Zhan</responsible>	   <collaborator>		   <collab><latin>Oliver Streiter</latin></collab>	   </collaborator>	   <description> 		   <div>This project aims at the documentation of human settlements. The very nature of a settlement is to enhance the chances of survival of a group of humans through physical and social arrangements they make. Parts of these arrangements are roads, neighborhoods, gardens etc.</div>		   <img alt="This image shows a village of Penghu located a the sea." style='width:75%' url="/2021/10/02/DATE20211002TIME134517GEOBOOLyesLONGE119515438LATN23652947DIRnoALT24SIZE256THUMB7536ORIGOliverDJI0039.jpg"/>	   </description>	   <url>/tml/menuSettlement.html</url></project><project id="franke">	   <name short="Wolfgang Franke" language="LGENG">Following the Footsteps of Wolfgang Franke in Southeast Asia</name>	   <responsible>Oliver Streiter, Yoann Goudin</responsible>	   <collaborator>		   <collab><latin>Fay Shi</latin></collab> 		   <collab><latin>Ya-Qing Zhan</latin></collab>		   <collab><latin>Lisa Streiter</latin></collab> 		   <collab><latin>Marcus Bingenheimer</latin></collab>	   </collaborator>	   <description>		   <div>The goal of this research project is to transform the paper-based and barely accessible Documentation of Chinese Epigraphy produced by Wolfgang Franke and his colleagues (WFCEM) into a permanently archived and freely accessible repository of standardized data that overlays the original documentation with state-of-the-art imagery, enhanced data, geo-localizations and a continuation of the prose describes of sites, object and inscriptions. Doing this we also hope to increase the awareness in various research communities of the existence of this extraordinarily rich resource, but also raise the awareness of those who manage and administer the cultural sites of the treasures history has laid into their hands.		   </div>		   <div> An epigraph is an inscription carved into an object composed of hardmaterial, such as stone, wood or metal.  Objects can be natural, such asrocks or trees, or man-made, such as stone steels or wooden tablets. Itis the object and its material culture that makes a difference between anepigraph and a text written on paper or a digital texts, as the latterones can be created, moved, modified and published showing no traceof their material nature and the place of its origin. The advantageof paper over stone, after all, is to allow texts to be moved and tobe stored, e.g. in libraries, independently from their conditions oforigin, representing universal ideas which can be brought to people ofdifferent regions and different cultures. Already medieval monks spent aconsiderable part of their lives copying books manually, an activity thathas been accelerated with the invention of the book printing, and later,with the ubiquity of digital media.		   </div>		   <div> The main distinctive features of epigraphs are their uniqueness and theircontext-dependency. Epigraphs, tend to remain on the site or the objecton which they have originally been created. It is the unique site and theunique object which contribute to the meaning of the epigraph. This isparticularly the case where deictic expressions are used to refer, e.g.,to a village as '本村' (běn cūn, this village), or '本廟'(ben3 miao4, this temple), instead of using the name of the village   or temple. Likewise, the oldest tombstone, the largest tombstone and    the only granite tombstone obtain these properties only within a set of  tombstones. People's names obtain meaning from nearby shops, factories  and temples, and family relations show how within a community familiesestablished and maintained their economic power.		   </div>		   <div>Wolfgang Franke was a well-known German Sinologist who taught in Hamburg University. He was the son of Otto Franke (1863-1946), the founder of German Sinology. After his retirement in 1977 Franke moved to Malaysia, where he continued to teach and pursue his research. Originally a specialist of the Ming Dynasty, Franke, perhaps influenced by the destruction of cultural assets during the Cultural Revolution (1966-1975), began to work on a large-scale photographic documentation of Chinese epigraphs in Southeast Asia. We will refer to this multi-volume survey of Chinese epigraphy in Malaysia, Indonesia, and Thailand as the Wolfgang Franke Chinese Epigraphic Materials (henceforth WFCEM).		   </div>		   <div>			   Franke assembled a large and effective team of collaborators that included renown scholars such as Chen Tieh Fan, Claudine Salmon, Anthony Siu and Porpan Juntaronanont, among others. How this team worked is almost undocumented and more research is needed to reveal how this team was able to collaborate successfully for such a long time.		   </div>		   <div>			   Building partially on data collected earlier in his career, WolfgangFranke began to intensify his fieldwork and assemble and publish amulti-volume documentation of Chinese epigraphic materials in Malaysia,Indonesia, and Thailand, covering the time span from the late Ming periodto the 1950s \cite{w.franke.malaysia.1}, \cite{w.franke.indonesia.1},\cite{w.franke.indonesia.3}, \cite{w.franke.thailand.1},\cite{w.franke.thailand.2}. He and his team were assisted by localscholars who were often crucial in identifying the oldest and most relevantepigraphs in a region.		   </div>		   <div>			   In two decades, the team around Wolfgang Franke documented and published approximately 10,000 inscriptions, the oldest and most relevant inscriptions they were able to find in the second half of the 20th century. This epigraphy is considered a crucial source for the study of overseas Chinese communities in Southeast Asia. Although in its present form it is difficult to access and cumbersome to use, it is absolutely indispensable for the serious study of Chinese religion and history in Southeast Asia.1. In total, the team around Wolfgang Franke published eight volumes on South East Asian Chinese epigraphy, each volume containing approximately 1000 epigraphs.		   </div>	   </description>	   <url>/tml/menuFranke.html</url></project><project id="bells"> 	   <name short="Bells" language="LGENG">Temple Bells in Pacific Asia</name>	   <responsible>Oliver Streiter</responsible>	   <collaborator>		   <collab><latin>Mandy To</latin></collab>	   </collaborator>	   <description>		   <div>Bells, like temple bells, if inscribed, are epigraphic objects of a particular kind.	           </div> 		   <div>As a sound instrument, they contribute to the sound-scape of a temple, and overlay the sounds-cape of a community partially with that of the temple. The sounds-cape of bells and temples thus belong to the intangible heritage of a community and merit to be preserved and researched.	           </div>		   <div>Secondly, bells, implicitly or explicitly, have also been used to structure time. This is e.g. very visible in the way that time is indicated in Thai. The way when the bells are struck and when not is an important way to understand how time is or has been structured in a community.</div>		   <div>Third, the sound properties of the bell are formed by the physical properties of the bell. It's material, it's shape and the type of clappers.	           </div> 		   <div>   Bells are also very interesting for the study of early settler history. As first generations of settlers wouldn't have the means to create bells locally, in the area of the new settlement, most bells would be acquired and the inscriptions on the bells, mentioning the foundry, allow to trace back economic relations, frequently with the region from where the settlers migrated from.	           </div>		   <img alt="This image shows a temple bell." style='width:75%' url="/2018/10/30/DATE20181030TIME171948GEOBOOLyesLONGE120610768LATN23749616DIRnoALT86SIZE30704THUMB8201ORIGsonyDSC02570.jpg"/>	       </description>	       <url>/tml/menuBell.html</url></project><project id="BangkokHokkien">	   <name short="Hokkien Cemetery" language="LGENG">The Hokkien Cemetery of Bangkok</name>	   <responsible>Oliver Streiter</responsible>	   <description>	   <div>In collaboration with Thammasat University, we are documenting and analyzing the Hokkien Cemetery of Bangkok.</div>	   <div>The Hokkien Cemetery is one of a few still existing Chinese cemeteries in Silom. It is very close to the Hakka cemetery, the Cantonese cemeteries and a few private Chinese burial sites at Silom Road. When set up about 130 years ago, the area of these cemeteries lay outside Saworat, outside the city fortification, and probably not related to any nearby settlement in an otherwise useless swampy land. The low area of these cemeteries is prone to flooding. For many weeks of the year some parts of these cemeteries are flooded, up to 10cm. Especially the east sides of the Hakka and Hokkien cemetery are prone to flooding, affecting not only the inscriptions and structures but also their value as an auspicious resting site. At the same time the price of the ground near the King Power Mahanakhon will increase the pressure to convert this land for commercial purposes. All in all, it is unlikely that these graveyards will remain in their current state for the decades to come and careful digital documentation is required.</div>	   <div>As Wolfgang Franke and Porpan Juntaronanont (1998) in their work on Chinese Epigraphy in Thailand documented only 10 tombstones in the Hokkien cemetery, and only 10 in the Hakka cemetery, most of the tombs, inscriptions, motifs and symbols remain undocumented and unexplored. It is the purpose of this research project to overcome the current gap in documentation and research of Chinese burial sites in Thailand, of the history of migration to Bangkok and the effect of migration onto the culture of the migrating communities in general.</div>	   </description>	   <url>/tml/menuBangkokHokkien.html</url></project></project>